

(228) 239-6088 toddlambert@gmail.com

highlights

Product Designer - Skilled web designer/developer with 21 years of professional experience.

Successful product designer able to integrate both technical and creative skills to create cross-browser and cross-platform solutions with modern web architecture and navigation systems.

Proven record of completing bold, clean, and effective designs with consistent performance ahead of schedule and under budget.

Industry experience including semiconductor, hospitality, entertainment, health, publishing, finance, insurance, construction, computer software, and direct marketing.

proficiency

Veteran WordPress Theme/Plugin Developer React JS Frontend Designer/Developer

Responsive, Reactive, Adaptive Design, progressive enhancement, PWA development, object oriented CSS animation.

Analytics, SEO, UI design, Information Architecture & Content Management System integrations. Photo and Video production.

I prefer: JAM stack, React, Gatsby, Canon, Subaru and my Mac.

education

- Cal State University Fullerton
 Web Design and Development Degree
- Coastline Community College Quality Assurance - Degree
- Golden West College
 Business Management Degree
- Huntington Beach High School
 High School General Courses Diploma

professional experience

Todd Lambert Enterprises, 1999 - Present

Sole Proprietor / Photographer

Conducted all facets of web development business including meeting with clients, selling web services, and developing methods for improved customer support.

I also like to travel all over the country and photograph spooky and abandoned places at night.

View @ TwilightScapes.com

☐

Primal Health, 2013 - 2014

Creative Director / Associate Developer

Responsible for all graphic components and direct marketing efforts. Worked with various departments to advance reach through social marketing, engineering and analytics. Also performed SEO and conducted extensive AB testing.

Texas Instruments, 2010 - 2013

Style Architect / Front End Developer / Senior UI Designer

Worked on all aspects of TIs website, from new ad campaigns and interactive widgets to the core infrastructure including a new re-design and replacement of site navigation site-wide. Championed responsive design techniques and other modern architecture for use on corporate site. Utilized Jquery animation for replacing all of TIs legacy Flash files.

AGJ Systems & Networks, 2008 - 2010

Web Director / Lead Developer / Senior Designer

Solely responsible for all design and development aspects of web department. Interacted with customers and other departments to integrate designs into modern websites catered to customer needs.

TeleVox Software, 2004 - 2007

Director of Web Development

Responsible for site architecture, design, graphics, programming, copywriting/editing, project management of all TeleVox websites and online marketing campaigns. Supervised 25 designers and developers.